





# BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER - NTUC, SINGAPORE

ONLINE http://bharathkumaraju.com

in in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraiu

CONTACT Singapore t: +65 90829964

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com

**BIO DETAILS** DOB: 12-June-1987

Passport: J7879295

## **SUMMARY:**

Over 8 years IT experience in DevOps and CLOUD in mission critical environments across the Streaming, Aviation, Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, automation, continuous deployment(CICD) pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

### **TECHNICAL PROFILE:**

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Terraform, Git, Bamboo, Vagrant, Docker, Github, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Functionbeat, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat, packetbeat. Monitoring/Log Sysdig, New relic, Datadog, App Dynamics, Sumologic, sensu, flapjack, Grafana, graphite.

Python, Shell Scripting, Java. Programming **RDBMS** Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

OS Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu, Coreos, Redhat Atomic

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform. Certifications AWS Solution Architect, Google cloud professional architect, Terraform certified professional

### **EXPERIENCE:**

NTUC Dockerized the applications and moved them from GCE VMs to cloud run serverless in Google cloud.

Singapore, Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for googlecloud.

(2020-2021) Implemented CICD Pipeline using Bitbucket pipelines to promote deployments seem lessly.

**HOOQ TV, Singapore** 

Automated AWS Cloud deployments and builds using the github actions. (2019-2020)

Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for AWS cloud were dockerized apps are running.

Working on openshift container platform to move legacy apps to k8s.

SingaporeAirlines,

Singapore (2019)

Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs. Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications.

Worked in k8s setup and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps.

Delivion GmBH,

Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD Essen, Germany pipeline. Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic (2017-2019)

Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution.

Standard Chartered, Chennai, India

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform.

(2014-2016)

Created Development, QA, Stage, Production stacks & maintained them securely using robust VPC design. Automated

resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort.

Implemented application monitoring using DataDog & integrated with AWS environment.

**Trimble Navigation,** Chennai, India (2012-2014)

Administered DHCP, DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Automating the

deployment of Middleware Applications to RHEL DEV/PROD servers on VMWare ESX.

#### **EDUCATION:**

MCA-Post Graduation (Jun2007-Jun2010)

Information System and Computer Science

UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

**BSC- Graduation** (Jul2004-May2007) Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics.

### **LANGUAGES:**

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

### **INTERESTS:**

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.